Okay, so let's go ahead and move through,
では 先に進んで 1 つずつ見ていき
step by step and talk about the LookAway node.
LookAway ノードについて話していきましょう
The imported modules are similar to those in simple arm,
インポートされたモジュールは simple arm のモジュールに
except this time we have
似ていますが ここではカメラデータを利用できるように
the image message type being imported so that the camera data can be used.
image メッセージタイプがインポートされています
Here, we define a class for this node to better keep track of
ここでは ロボットアームの現在の移動状態と位置履歴をより正確に追跡できるように
the robot arms current movement state and position history.
このノードのクラスを定義します
Just as in the node definitions before,
前のノードの定義のように
the node is initialized using the rospy.init_node function.
ノードは rospy.init_node 関数を使用して初期化されます
And at the end of the method,
メソッドの最後に
rospy.spin is used to block until a shutdown request is received by the node.
rospy.spin を使用して シャットダウン要求がノードによって受信されるまでブロックします
The first subscriber, self.sub1,
最初のサブスクライバー self.sub1 は
subscribes to the simple_arm/joint_states topic.
simple_arm/joint_states トピックにサブスクライブします
The node is written to check the camera only when the arm is not moving.
ノードは arm が動いてないときはカメラのみを確認するように記述されます
And by subscribing to simple_arm/joint_state,
simple_arm/joint_state にサブスクライブすることで
changes in the position of the arm can be tracked.
arm 位置の変化を追跡することができます
The message type for this topic is joint_state and with each message,
このトピックのメッセージタイプはjoint_stateで
the message data is passed to the joint_states_callback function.
メッセージごとにメッセージデータはjoint_state_callback関数に渡されます
The second subscriber, self.sub2,
2 つ目のサブスクライバー self.sub2 は
subscribes to the rgb_camera/image _raw topic.
rgb_camera/image _raw トピックにサブスクライブします
The message type here is image and with each message,
このメッセージタイプはimageで、メッセージごとにメッセージ
the look_away_callback function is called.
データはlook_away_callback関数に渡されます
A service proxy is how rospy enables calling a service from a node.
サービスプロキシは ノードからサービスを呼び出せる方法です
The service proxy here is created using the name of the service you wish to call,
ここの service proxy は 呼び出したいサービスの名前と
along with the service class definition.
サービスクラス定義を使って作成されます
In this case, arm_mover/safe_move, and go to position.
この場合arm_mover/safe_moveとGoToPositionです
The actual calls to the service will take place in the look_away_callback method.
実際のサービスへの呼び出しは look_away_callback メソッドで行われます
There are two helpers defined in the code,
コードでは 2 つのヘルパーが定義されています
uniform underscore image, and coord underscore equa.l.
uniform_image と coord_equa.l です
The uniform_image method takes an image as input and checks if
uniform_image メソッドは画像を入力として取得し
all color values in the image are the same as the color value as the first pixel.
画像のすべてのカラー値が最初のピクセルの値と同じであるかどうかを確認します
This essentially checks that all color values in the image are the same.
つまり 画像のすべてのカラー値が同じであることを確認します
The coord_equal method returns true if the coordinates coord_1
coord_equal メソッドは 座標 coord_1
and coord_2 have equal components up to the specified tolerance.
および coord_2 が指定許容値を上限として等しい成分を持つ場合 true を返します
When self.sub1 receives a message on the simple_arm/joint _states topic,
self.sub1 が simple_arm/joint _states トピックでメッセージを受信するとき
the message is passed to the joint_states_callback in the variable data.
メッセージはjoint_states_callback関数に変数dataで渡されます
The joint_states_callback uses the coord_equal helper function to check if
joint_states_callbackはcoord_equal ヘルパー関数を使用して
the current joint_states provided in data are the same as the previous joint_states,
データで提供された現在のjoint_statesが
which are stored in self.last_position.
self.last_position に保存されている前の joint_states と同じかどうか確認します
If the current and previous joint_states are the same,
現在の joint_states と前のが同じ場合
up to the specified tolerance,
指定許容値を上限とし
then the arm has stopped moving.
arm は動きを停止します
So, the self.arm_moving flag is set to false.
よって self.arm_moving フラグは false に設定されます
If the current and previous joint_states are different,
現在の joint_states と前のが異なる場合
the arm is still moving.
アームはまだ動き続けています
In this case, the method updates self.last_position with
この場合 メソッドは現在の位置データで
current position data and sets self.arm_moving to true.
self.last_position を更新し self.arm_moving を true に設定します
The look_away_ callback is receiving data from the rgb_camera/image_raw topic.
look_away_ callback は rgb_camera/image_raw topic からデータを受信しています
The first line of this method verifies that the arm is not moving and also checks
このメソッドの最初の行は アームが移動していないことを検証し
if the image is uniform.
画像が均一かどうかを確認します
If the arm isn't moving and the image is uniform,
arm が動いてなくて画像が均一である場合は
then GoToPositionRequest message is created and sent using the safe_move service,
GoToPositionRequest メッセージが作成されて safe_move サービスを使用して送信され
moving both joint angles to 1.57.
両方のジョイント角が 1.57 に移動します
The method also logs a message warning you that the camera has detected
また このメソッドは カメラがよりいい画像を返すために経過した時間で均一な画像を検出したという
a uniform image along with the elapsed time to return a nicer.
警告メッセージをログに記録します